Cambridge ielts four by university
of Cambridge esol examinations
published by Cambridge university press
this recording is copyright
cd one test one you'll hear a number of different recordings
and you'll have to answer questions on what you hear there will
be time for you to read the instructions and questions
and you will have a chance to check your work
all the recordings will be played once only
the test is in four sections
at the end of the test
you'll be given ten minutes to transfer
your answers to an answer sheet
now turn to section one
section i  you'll hear a young student asking
the social organiser of his school
for information about organized trips  first
you have some time to look at questions one to four
you'll see that there is an example which has been done for you
on this occasion only
the conversation relating to this will be played first
good morning
how can i help you
i understand that the school organises um trips to different
yes  we run five every month
three during weekends and two Wednesday afternoon trips
there are five trips every month
so five has been written in the notes
now we shall begin
you should answer the questions as you listen
because you will not hear the recording a second time
listen carefully and answer questions one to four
good morning
how can i help you
i understand that the school organizes um trips to different
yes  we run five every month
three during weekends and two Wednesday afternoon trips
what sort of places  well
obviously it varies
but always places of historical interest
and also which offer a variety of shopping
because our students always ask about that
and then we go for ones where we know there are guided tours
because this gives a good focus for the visit
do travel far  well
we're lucky here obviously
because we're able to say that all our
visits are less than three hours drive
how much do they cost  again
it varies between five and fifteen pounds a head
depending on distance
oh  and we do offer to arrange special trips
if you know
there are more than twelve people  all right
i'll keep that in mind
and what are the times normally
we try to keep it pretty fixed
so that that students get to know the pattern
we leave at eight thirty am and return at six pm
we figure it's best to keep the day fairly short  oh  yes
and how do we reserve a place
you sign your name on the notice board
do you know where it is  uh huh
i saw it this morning
and we do ask that you sign up three days in advance
so we know we've got enough people interested to run it
and we can cancel if necessary with full refund of course
that's fine  thanks
符
before you hear the rest of the conversation
you have some time to look at questions five to ten
你
now listen and answer questions five to ten
and what visits are planned for this term  right  well
i'm afraid the schedule hasn't been printed out yet
but we have confirmed the dates and
planned the optional extra visits
which you can also book in advance if you want to  oh
that's all right
if you can just give some idea of the weekend ones
so i can you know work out when to see friends etc  oh  sure
well  uh
the first one is st ives
that's on the thirteenth of February
and we'll have only sixteen places available  uh
cause we're going by minibus
and that's a day in town with the optional
extra of visiting the heythrop museum  all right  yeah
that sounds good
then there's a London trip on the sixteenth of February
and we'll be taking a medium sized coach
so there'll be forty five places on that
and let's see the optional extra is the tower of London  oh
i've already been there  yeah  after that
there's Bristol on the third of March  where  Bristol
b R I S T O l  OK
that's um in a different minibus
with eighteen places available
oh
and the optional extra is a visit to the ss great Britain  OK
we're going to Salisbury on the eighteenth of March
and that's always a popular one
because the optional extra is stonehenge  so
we're taking the large coach with fifty seats  oh  good
and then the last one is to bath on the twenty third of March
oh  yes
is Bath the Roman city  yes
that's right
and that's in the sixteen seater minibus
and where's the optional visit
it's to the American museum
well worth a visit  OK
well that's great
thanks for all that
my pleasure  oh  by the way
if you want more information about any of the trips
have a look in the student newspaper  OK
or have a word with my assistant
her name is Jane yentob
That's Y E N T O B  all right
i've got that
thank you very much for all your help
you're very welcome
i hope you enjoy the trips
that is the end of section one
you now have half a minute to check your answers
now turn to section two